# **Benjamin Pearce**

#### Contact

Address: 25 Welbeck Rise,

Harpenden, Hertfordshire, AL5 1RT

Email: ben.pearce25@gmail.com

#### Portfolio:

https://benp99.github.io/portfolio/

**Mobile:** 07443479846

### **Skills**

- Unity (2D and 3D)
- C#
- Visual Studio
- C and C++
- Java
- Python
- HTML
- CSS and SASS
- JavaScript and Typescript
- Angular JS
- jQuery
- SQL
- Azure
- GitHub and GitBash
- Microsoft Office Programs
- Libre Office Programs
- Photoshop
- Agile Methodologies
  - o SCRUM

#### **Awards**

Nominated for BCS Innovation Award for BSc Final Project

School Graduation Prize for achieving an exceptionally high result (University of Hertfordshire)

### **Hobbies**

- Make and produces music using FL Studio
- Played Squash
- Studied Ju Jitsu, a form of Martial Arts
- Design and develop projects in my spare time, like games and my portfolio
- Video Games

# **Personal Summary**

I am a passionate developer which my specialities being games and website development. One of my biggest achievements was the completion of my three year course at the University of Hertfordshire, the course being BSc (Hons) Computer Science (Software Engineering) which I completed with a 1st.

As this course had a specialisation in software engineering I learnt a lot about the principles and practices which I still use to this day. As a highly motivated and experienced developer, both in professional work environments and personal projects, I have gained experience with games and website development proven by the projects shown in my portfolio and the professional work experience I have gained. Because of this experience I have a proven ability to work within teams of developers to produce quality solutions, but also the ability to learn and adapt in new work environments.

# **Education and Qualifications**

### 2017-2021 University of Hertfordshire

Course: BSc (Hons) Computer Science (Software Engineering) Achieved First Class

### 2015-2017 **Bedford College**

Course: BTEC Level 3 Diploma in IT

Achieved Double Grade Distinction\* Distinction\*

# 2010-2015 Sir John Lawes

**GCSE** 

### **Work Experience**

### July 2021-Present

### Web Developer

#### Iken

- Agile SCRUM environment
- Weekly sprint meetings
- Daily SCRUM meetings
- Meetings for acceptance criteria for user stories
- Develop new features stated in User Stories
- Fix raised bugs
- Review pull requests of work committed by other developers

# August 2019-July 2020

## Front End Developer

### eArcu

- Develop recruitment sites for clients
- Talk with product and clients about designs and requirements for new sites
- QA other developers work on other recruitment sites
- Fix bugs on existing recruitment sites

# January 2019-January 2021

#### Freelance Web Developer

- Meeting with client for designs and requirements for the site
- Meetings with client to update on the sites progress
- Develop a website for the client (link to the site on my

### Languages

English

# References

Mr. Sam Liddy

Email: sam.liddy@earcu.com

Miss. Joanne Smith

Email:

Joanne.Smith1@hertfordshire.gov.uk

portfolio)

Helping client host the finished site on a hosting service

# February 2017 Infrastructure Engineer

Lumesse Ltd

- Take apart old servers in the company's server room, removing unused RAM needed for other devices
- Deleting old logical drives
- Other maintenance on older devices

### February 2016 **Customer Service**

Barclays Bank

- Helping people work ATMs
  - Shadowing front desk
  - Other customer facing roles

### June 2014 Front End Developer

Lumesse Ltd

Develop recruitment sites for clients, frontend and database

### **Volunteer Work**

November

**IT Champion** 

2016-June 2017 St Albans Library

- Troubleshooting
- Helping users with tech queries from simple to more complex queries

### May 2019- **Club Supervisor**

December 2022 Harpenden Warhammer and Tabletop Games

- Organise and plan club events, and help run said events
- Referee games
- Make sure the members are getting along